dccebooks.com 2018-06-27

# Privacy Policy | David C Cook

_Updated May 2018_

  1. Welcome and Introduction
  2. The Information We Collect
  3. How We Use the Personal Information We Collect
  4. Marketing
  5. Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties
  6. Transfers of your Personal Information outside of the European Union
  7. Your Rights
  8. Children’s Privacy
  9. Security
  10. Information You Make Publicly Available
  11. Third Party Sites
  12. Visitors From Outside of the United States
  13. Governing Law
  14. Changes to Privacy Policy
  15. Effective Date

* * *

## **Welcome and Introduction**

Welcome to David C Cook (including our divisions and affiliates, “we” or “us” or “our”), we operate a number of different websites. These include davidccook.org, sundayschool.com, and integritymusic.com. The following provisions apply to your use of our websites and the data collection and privacy practices of our websites. Please take a moment to review this policy carefully. If you choose to visit our sites, the personal data you provide or which is collected as a result of your visit is subject to these policies, including application of the law of Colorado. Your personal data will be processed and stored under the responsibility of David C Cook. Your visit or submission of information to us through our websites, our customer service department, or purchase by other means signifies that you fully accept the terms, conditions, and practices of this policy.

For information on the **Cookies** we use, please read our Cookie Policy.

For questions or requests regarding this Privacy Policy, our Data Protection Officer can be reached via email at privacy@davidccook.com. Our postal address is: 4050 Lee Vance Dr, Colorado Springs, CO 80918.

## **The Information We Collect**

_Non-Personal Information_. We may collect the domain name of your Internet service provider, usage statistics and other non-personal data about your visit to our site but this information is not linked to your personally identifiable information.

_Personal Information.  _We collect information which may identify you (“Personal Information”), such as your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, fax number, IP address, credit card or other payment information, age, birthdate, login name, password, denomination, religious beliefs and place of worship. We may collect Personal Information from you when you visit our website, post on our bulletin boards, comment, use chat areas and any other personal data which you supply to us from time to time.

Certain services or products we offer may be tailored to a specific denomination. As such, we may ask you to identify your place of worship. You will, of course, have the option to decline to provide this information; however, if it is required for a particular service or product, you will be unable to obtain that service or product if you decline to provide it.

## **How We Use the Personal Information We Collect**

We may use the information we collect, including IP addresses, to:

**Personal Information**  
---  
**Purpose of processing** | **Legal basis of processing**  
Perform a contract for the purchase of products, purchased or downloaded from this website | Processing is necessary in order to perform the contract of goods that we entered in to with you  
Provide services or products or complete transactions that you request and retain an internal record of providing those services or products | Processing is necessary in our legitimate interest to provide our services, and maintain an internal record of providing those services and products  
Provide order status or feedback request from you | Processing is necessary in order to perform the contract of goods or services that we entered in to with you  
Create your user account | Processing is based on consent  
To protect against fraud | Processing is necessary in our legitimate interests to manage our risk of fraud  
Administer our site | Processing is in the legitimate interests of our business to manage the site  
Engage with any correspondence/ communications received (including on the phone or via online chats) | Processing is in the legitimate interest of responding to any communications we receive from you  
Run surveys/polls/ questionnaires | Processing is based on consent  
Run contests | Processing is based on consent  
Analyze trends and use of content on our site | Processing is in the legitimate interests of our business to effectively manage our content and site visitors, and also to improve our services  
Track user movements and interaction with content on our site, via cookies | Processing is in the legitimate interests of our business to effectively manage our content and site visitors, and also to improve our services 

For further information, please see our Cookie Policy [davidccook.org/cookie-policy]  
  
Allow access to limited entry areas of the website | Processing is in the legitimate interests of our business to manage access to restricted areas of the site  
Gather broad demographic information for use on an aggregated basis | Processing is in the legitimate interests of our business to understand our audience and improve our services  
Notify you about updates to our Terms and Conditions of Use, and Privacy Policy | Processing is in the legitimate interests of us both, to make you aware of our current terms  
Market – notify you about updates to our websites, product offerings, ministry or your profile content | Processing is either: 

–       in the legitimate interests of our business to tell you about our news because you are already a customer and we have given you an opportunity to opt out

or

–       you have consented to receiving this information  
  
**Special Categories of Personal Data – Information revealing religious beliefs**  
---  
**Purpose of processing** | **Legal basis of processing**  
Facilitate the hosting of materials that you post | Processing is on the basis of your consent  
Facilitate and manage the messaging platform that you may use | Processing is on the basis of your consent  
Tailor services or products | Processing is based on your consent, and the information is optional to the service being requested  
Run surveys/polls/questionnaires | Processing is based on consent  
Engage with any correspondence/communications received (including on the phone or via online chats) | Processing is based on your consent, information is voluntarily provided 

Or

Processing is in relation to a legal claim  
  
Analyze trends and use of content on our site | Processing is based on consent  
Gather broad demographic information for use on an aggregated basis | Processing is based on consent  
  
## **Marketing**

_Postal Marketing_

If you supply us with your postal address and opt in to receiving such information, you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services.

_Telephone Marketing_

If you supply us with your telephone number and opt in to receiving calls and texts, you may receive telephone contact from us with information regarding new products and services.

_Email Marketing_

If you supply us with their email address and opt in to marketing emails, you may receive emails from us with information regarding new products and services from us.

_Marketing from our chosen third parties_

Where you provide express consent for us to do so, we may:

  * send an email to you on behalf of a partner ministry;
  * share your Personal Information with other companies in our group, record labels, publishers, authors (or their agents), artists (or their agents) and or our partner ministries, who are offering products or services that we believe may be of service or interest to you, or who may contact you with an offer or advertisement, or they may use such information for their own research or business purposes, or other purposes you agree to.

## **Disclosure of Personal Information**

To help us provide you with superior service, timely completion of purchases and returns, as well as accurate shipments, we may share certain information relating to you within the David C Cook corporate family of entities which we are part of. We may also share certain Personal Information with strategic, co-branded, or joint partners and with third party processors and vendors, as necessary, to process your orders or requests and otherwise administer the account (however, we will only share credit or debit card information as required to effectively process your credit or debit card payment, or to analyze trends or usage of our website). These entities help us provide many important services to you, such as extending credit, fulfilling and shipping orders, providing customer service and performing customer satisfaction surveys.

We may also share information with third parties to verify information collected from you in order to protect against potential fraud, and we may receive Personal Information about you from these parties.

Your election to opt-out of the data sharing within the “Your Rights” section entitled “How to Opt Out of Future Communications” is not an opt-out for the data sharing described in this paragraph.

On occasion, we may be (or have a good faith belief that we are) required by law or litigation to disclose Personal Information pertaining to you. We may also disclose such information if we determine that for national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance or safety, disclosure is necessary. At times, we may share Personal Information in aggregate, so that no one individual can be identified (i.e., anonymous).

We may also transfer Personal Information to a third party as a result of a sale or acquisition, merger, or bankruptcy involving us.

_Independent Contractors_

From time to time, we may use certain independent contractors and other third parties to operate components of our site, fulfill orders, or assist us in operating or improving our site.  In this capacity, we may allow these independent contractors and third parties to collect the information described in this Privacy Policy for us.

## **Transfers of your Personal Information outside of the European Union**

If you choose to provide us with Personal Information, we may transfer that information to our affiliates, subsidiaries, other third parties or processors, to other countries or jurisdictions around the world, including outside of the EU.

_Visiting from the European Union_

Transfers to members of our Group

We may transfer your Personal Information to other members of our group, located in the United States. Your Personal Information is transferred subject to appropriate safeguards, in the form of an agreement including the model contract clauses provided by the European Commission. You have the right to request a copy of this agreement by contacting us on the details set out in the introduction. Please note, we reserve the right to redact elements for commercial sensitivity.

Transfers to third party providers

We may transfer your Personal Information to third party providers that we use to operate this website, located outside of the EU. Where we transfer your Personal Information to third party providers we ensure your Personal Information has an adequate level of protection. The third party providers are either based in a country which has an adequacy decision by the Commission (including the EU-US Privacy Shield), for more information, visit http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/adequacy/index_en.htm, or we have entered into model contract clauses with them.

## **Data Retention**

We only keep your information for as long as necessary in relation to the purpose for which we are processing that information. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

We maintain a data retention policy which we apply to all data in our care. Where your personal information is no longer required we will ensure it is securely deleted.

## **Your Rights**

Data protection laws give you rights in relation to the Personal Information we hold about you. In certain circumstances, we may need to restrict your rights in order to safeguard the public interest (e.g. the prevention or detection of crime) and our interests (e.g. the maintenance of legal privilege).

Unless otherwise stated below, please use the contact information in the introduction regarding exercising these rights. In order to evaluate these requests we may require additional information to confirm your identity.

## **_Your California Privacy Rights_**

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents who provide Personal Information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain once a calendar year information from us about the Personal Information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of Personal Information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared such information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2015 will receive information regarding 2014 sharing activities).

To obtain this information, please send an email message to the address provided above with “Request for California Privacy Information” in the subject line and in the body of your message. The requested information, if required by law, will be provided to you at your email inbox.

**_If you are visiting our site from the European Union – Your Rights_**

These rights may include the right to require us to:

  * provide you with further details on how use your Personal Information
  * provide you with access to your Personal Information
  * update any inaccuracies in the Personal Information we hold about you
  * delete any of your Personal Information
  * where processing is based on consent, stop that particular processing by withdrawing your consent
  * object to any processing based on our legitimate interests unless our reasons for undertaking that processing outweigh any prejudice to your data protection rights
  * restrict how we use your Personal Information
  * transfer your Personal Information to a third party in a standardised machine-readable format

Please note that these rights are limited and there may be reasons why these requests cannot be fulfilled.

**_How to Opt Out of Future Communications_**

If you would like to opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us or our partners in the future, please let us know by visiting us at [www.davidccook.com/unsubscribe/cfm](http://www.davidccook.com/unsubscribe/cfm). (Unsubscribe links are also included at the bottom of marketing and promotional emails.)

Please note: unsubscribing from marketing and promotional communications will not prevent us from sending you communications to inform you about other issues relating to our existing relationship with you, including but not limited to, confirming an order, updating you on order status, product recalls, and informing you about changes to our terms and conditions and this Privacy Policy.

**_Supervisory Authority_**

If you are not satisfied with our use of your Personal Information or our response to any request by you to exercise your data protection rights, or if you think that we have breached any relevant data protection laws, then you have the right to complain to the authority that supervises our processing of your Personal Information. If you are unsure of the authority that supervises our processing of your Personal Information then please contact us for further guidance.

## **Children’s Privacy**

Our site is not directed to children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect or maintain information on children under the age of 13.

If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit Personal Information to us.

If you are the parent or guardian of a child age 13 or under who has provided us with Personal Information and you would like that information removed, please contact us via the details provided in the Introduction.

_Content Submitted by California Minors_

If you are under the age of 18 and reside in California, you may request that we remove or make anonymous any content you have posted to our website.

Please contact us at the email address provided above with the phrase “Privacy Rights for California Minors in the Digital World Request” in the subject line and body of your email. We may decide at our discretion whether to remove the requested content or allow it to remain on our website but remove all indications of the individual who posted it.

## **Security**

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on all website pages where Personal Information appears or is collected. If you wish to make a purchase from our website, you must use an SSL-enabled browser (for example, Firefox, Internet Explorer, or Safari). We use 128 bit encryption in our SSL sessions to protect personal customer information, including credit card information transmitted to our website for making purchases.

When we transfer and receive certain types of financial information such as credit card numbers during the order checkout process, we redirect you to a secure server. We follow Payment Card Industry (PCI) standards in the handling of your credit card information.

For any website to which you have an account login and password, you can help us protect your Personal Information by keeping your account password confidential at all times and by not sharing it with any other person. You should also change your password frequently and be sure to use a combination of letters and numbers.

Unfortunately, no security system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee the security of your information and cannot assume liability for improper access to it. By using any service we provide, including our website and user interfaces, or providing information to us through any means, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of any such service or our website.

## **Information You Make Publicly Available**

You should be aware that information (including your name, email address, address, or phone number) provided by you in a posting on the website or any public page, bulletin board or social media site or function is available (even after you stop participating on the website) to any other individual who has access to that same website and may be used by another individual in a manner unintended by you, including as a target for unsolicited communications. You should therefore treat any information provided by you in the content of a submission or post to the website as public information. For this reason, we urge you to act cautiously in providing any such information in your submissions or posts, as we are not liable for any use or misuse by an individual user of the information you provide in a submission or post.

## **Third Party Sites**

This Privacy Policy applies only to this website. Other websites we own and websites owned or operated by third parties may contain different privacy policies and practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any other person, entity, organization, or website to or from which the website links or is linked. You are strongly encouraged to read and regularly review posted privacy policies on all websites, whether or not owned by us or affiliated with the site.

## **Visitors From Outside of the United States**

This Privacy Policy applies to all visitors in the United States and to visitors from outside the United States to the extent allowed by applicable law. This site and the servers upon which it is hosted are located in the United States. This site is governed by the laws of the State of Colorado in the United States.

## **Governing Law**

The law governing this website and any disputes arising out of a visit to this website, including privacy, shall be governed by Colorado law.

## **Changes to Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change the content of its website and of this Privacy Policy at any time and at its sole discretion. For example, from time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not disclosed in our previous Privacy Policy notices. We will provide notice of changes to our Privacy Policy, but please check this site frequently for changes.  You are bound by any changes to the policy when you visit or use our site after those changes have been posted. Unless stated otherwise, these policies apply to any information provided by you and stored in our records.

## **Effective Date**

The Privacy Policy posted on this website was updated in May 2018.

x

We use cookies to allow you to log-in to your account, to store payment details and analyze your activities on this website, and to improve your experience on this website and our services. By accessing this website, you agree to our cookies policy. [More info](https://davidccook.org/cookie-policy/). Got It!
